RENAE SOWALD

Bothell, WA 98012
937-902-8398 | renaesowald@gmail.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/renae-sowald/ | https://github.com/rsowald
https://rsowald.github.io/react_portfolio/

SUMMARY

I am trained as a Full Stack Web Developer specializing in the MERN stack. However, I have been a technical writer for the last 2 and a half years. Most of my academic experience was in the humanities with a focus on writing, and adding development knowledge made my skill set perfectly tailored to technical writing. I now have experience writing both JavaScript applications and comprehensive accompanying reference materials. Using my research, writing, and coding skills, I also enjoy the challenge of reading technical documents and creating a precis for a team in my own terms. I feel that I could be a passionate, collaborative, and constructive member of a technical writing team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, ES6, HTML 5, CSS 3, NodeJS, SQL (MySQL), NoSQL (Mongo) **Libraries and Applications:** npm, Materialize, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, Sequelize, Mongoose,

Express, Heroku, React.js, Next.js, Vue, Vite, Swagger, Docker, Docusaurus

Concepts: MVC, responsive design, agile methodologies

Spoken Languages: English, Spanish, German

EXPERIENCE

Event Store, Bothell, WA – Technical Documentation Writer AUGUST 2023 - JULY 2024

- Edited existing documentation by improving wording, adding information for clarity, and removing duplicate information.
- Worked with documentation as code, following Git workflows.
- Gained working knowledge of operational databases and event sourcing.
- Built a documentation site from scratch with React-based site generator Docusaurus.
- Gained more experience with agile development and project management tools.

SignalWire, Bothell, WA – Technical Documentation Writer FEBRUARY 2022 - AUGUST 2023

- Wrote product documentation at varying levels of technical detail from traditional tech reference to marketing copy.
- Created applications to demonstrate APIs and wrote accompanying code guides.
- Reviewed and edited code and guides from the documentation team.
- Edited articles from the marketing team.

Stay-At-Home Parent, Bothell, WA JUNE 2014 - FEBRUARY 2022

- Gained the ability to handle multiple competing priorities in a fast-paced environment.
- Honed patience into a skill to succeed in tedious, difficult, or even uncomfortable situations.
- Developed a love for teaching with the ability to adapt mentoring style to different personalities and learning styles.

Pier 1 Imports, Bellevue, WA — Sales Leader AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2014

• Frequently led my team to sales totaling 20% over our target.

- Provided excellent customer service, specializing in service issues and time consuming design projects.
- Coached and mentored up to 5 employees at a time.
- Adapted corporate directives and strategies to practicable goals and guidelines.
- Completely set new displays 4 times a year, starting from scratch and finishing in 3 days or less.

PROJECTS

MyLitLife | https://github.com/rsowald/MyLitLife | https://my-lit-life.herokuapp.com/ A web application to track reading lists and reading history. A user can find book recommendations as well as save reading notes, opinions, and ratings for each book.

- Collaborated closely with 5 team members to create a dynamic React user interface.
- Built reusable React components that could be used across multiple pages.
- Maintained a Mongo database with Mongoose models.
- Gathered, evaluated, and incorporated user feedback.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure high quality before changes were integrated.

Technology used — React, Firebase authorization, MongoDb, Heroku deployment, React Bootstrap, JS, HTML

Meal Planner | https://github.com/rsowald/MealPlanner | https://rsowald.github.io/MealPlanner/ Search for recipe ideas by meal name and save your recipe links to a built-in weekly calendar. Meal Planner also has a random cocktail button that will present you a cocktail recipe to go with your meal.

- Created a stable, collaborative and supportive work environment with 4 peers.
- Researched and implemented new technologies including multiple REST APIs.
- Daily troubleshooting issues and problem solving as necessary.

Technology used — AJAX, jQuery, client local storage, Materialize CSS, JS, HTML

I Blog Technically | https://github.com/rsowald/TechBlog | https://rhubarb-cobbler-10166.herokuapp.com/ Similar to WordPress, authenticated users can create, edit, or delete their own blog posts. They can also comment on other users' posts.

- Focused on the customer experience to create a streamlined UI with the Handlebars.js framework.
- Developed a robust SQL database utilizing Sequelize.
- Self motivated to meet and exceed expectations for the project.

Technology used — Node.js, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Express, Heroku with Jaws Db, Bootstrap CSS, JS, HTML

EDUCATION

University of Washington Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp - Certificate

DEC 2020 - JUNE 2021

• A 24 week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and React JS.

The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH — BA History, BA English

SEPT 2005 - JUNE 2009

• Magna Cum Laude GPA 3.84